How are you?
>> Good.
>> Doing good. Um, all right. You guys
ready? Um, yeah, we're really excited
about Monroe. Um, best player on our
board. Uh, big, long, athletic,
physical, a guy with high upside that
we're extremely excited about. Um,
adding him to our room. Um, you know,
think he can play left side, he can play
right side.
um brings, you know, a lot of value to
us. Um so yeah, we're really excited. Um
best player on the board and um I'll
leave it to coach if you want to say
anything.
>> Uh yeah, just first of all just like the
work that went into this, you know, with
Dan and the crew. uh pretty amazing to
be able to boil this thing down. So, we
knew exactly what we were going to do um
when we got to that and uh and the way
it played out, you know, he he came
right to us and this was a you know um a
guy that we really valued and for us of
course our philosophy is always let's
challenge our roster. Let's challenge
every room with great players and to get
an opportunity to have a guy like this
with athletic ability, the length, uh
size and all that. It's just it's
incredible. Um so we'll get him in
there. We'll let him compete. That's
what he'll be doing on the field.
>> How much
Uh, we can open it up. You're good.
>> How much did Icky's um injury factor
into you guys decision?
>> Um, Icky, he's doing great. Um, he's
he's making a lot of progress and yeah,
we we like where he's headed. Um, I
think more than anything we our biggest
thing is we want to keep both our front
strong and to add a big long talented
tackle um here in the first round like
it keeps our offensive line strong.
Having drafted an offensive lineman
since I've been here um and to be able
to add somebody with the talent that
Monroe has uh was it was just too good
to pass up.
>> You guys you guys had at the meetings
that you did not really even drafting
for depth. Do you think this is a depth
pick or could he be a day one starter?
>> Uh we're always just going to try to
challenge every room and the way we do
that is by picking the best player um
that fits that and so that's what this
approach was. It's pretty consistent
with our philosophy of just challenging
the roster in different ways and then of
course the best player available.
>> Is there a longterm approach with this
guys? Um I mean obviously Taylor's 31,
he's played 145 games. Um he's coming
off a new I mean Is there shortterm?
Maybe play him at left tackle, move him
to right tackle. Is there kind of a long
term or
>> We're going to figure all that out. Um
right now we just got to get them in
here, talk to them, get them on the
field. Um most of our guys outside of
Teemo and Icky, most of our guys end up
playing both sides throughout camp.
That's just kind of the way we do it. Uh
to give us flexibility. Um so, but too
early to tell. What I do know is he's
going to have a chance to compete. Um
that's our philosophy. That's how we
believe in doing things here. Um and
we'll give him that chance. How much of
an advantage is it having the way you
guys use the offensive line coaches
where Joe's going to probably be
tutoring him pretty hands-on one-on-one
and and how much did that factor into
how you wanted to weigh the value of
this pick?
>> Yeah, I mean it's it's amazing to have
that flexibility. You know, you talked
about Joe and Goody, uh two guys that I
really trust who were really wondering
if I didn't like them because we hadn't
selected any uh linemen in in the last
couple of drafts. But no, they're
they're fired up and it it works out
really well, especially when you bring
in a young player um cuz he's really got
his personal tutor, you know, and um and
Joe does such an excellent job and and
did that in Tampa as well. And um he's
going to be, you know, it's going to be
all hands- on deck and be really
involved with Monero's uh development.
>> Can you take us through just how the
draft went through and how your how it
how your board came through with the
earlier picks and did it fall the way
that you think? I think it was uh it was
falling our way. Um I think as the picks
kept coming off, I think we were getting
a little more nervous. Uh we had a
couple guys that we had our eye on and
um it just so happened that you know
Monroe was there at at our pick and
again he's just too good to pass up. Um
to be that big, long and athletic and
and young. Um yeah, it was it was
something that we we weren't sure if he
was going to be there. We thought he
might get taken a little sooner. Um, so
when he was there, it was it was easy
pick for us.
>> Did you guys explore the trading up at
all?
>> Uh, no, we didn't. We didn't. We um, you
know, we we wanted to sit there and just
keep our picks and let it come to us.
Um, of course, like we'll have our
little conversations about should we or
should we not, but at the end of the
day, we just wanted to stay put and let
somebody come to us, keep our picks, and
keep drafting. talked a bit about uh
wanting to learn about the person who
you're going to be selecting and their
story. What did you learn about him and
his character that he's going to be?
>> Oh, he's he's an unbelievable kid. Um
you know, just always, you know, happy,
great smile, like he he loves football.
Um part of which is huge for Dave and I
and the rest of the staff is to get guys
that love football, are passionate about
being great. And you felt that from
Monroe every single time you talked to
him. He just loves the game. He loves
competing. He's tough. Um so he brings
everything that we were looking for
>> both of you guys. There wasn't a lot of
tape to look at. 18 career starts, but
what jumped out at that tape? Was there
a game? Was there a play or a series of
plays that that impressed you?
>> I mean, I think you can take it all the
way through the season. And I mean, you
know, you you look at a guy that's 6'7,
has 34 inch arms, huge hands. Uh he's
just an athlete out there, an athlete
that can pass, protect, he can mirror,
um you know, run, block, get to the
second level, he can move the line of
scrimmage. He just does so many things
well that excited us. and and again he's
just the type of person that we want um
you know from a player standpoint and
also somebody we wanted to you know
bring into that locker room.
>> View on that question.
>> Yeah, same. Yeah, same. really just uh
for me, you always start with the
athletic profile and um to get a guy
that's 21 years old um who's for all
intents and purposes hasn't fully grown
into his body completely, you know, but
to already be 67 and, you know, 315
pounds, you know, like um he's going to
settle into some really good football.
The strength and all that stuff will
continue to develop. But um we kind of
start there with the movement skills and
length and uh it's those two things, the
quickness, you know, his straight line
speed, length, all that's very forgiving
for an offensive lineman. Um that's what
really fired me up about his film.
>> Is there an advantage to not having that
experience and being a little bit maybe
more moldable? I know you've talked
about with quarterbacks, you want guys
that are trained, but also with a guy
who has the athletic traits and the type
of blocking scheme you do to be able to
kind of mold him the way you want to. Is
there an advantage there?
You'd always like guys to have more
games, um, more experience that way. I
just know, uh, different scenarios
happen in the game. Um, but to your
point, you know, having a guy that, you
know, has limited starts when you get
them, um, you really do have a chance to
to imprint on them just our style,
philosophy, and techniques and drills
and all those things. But, um, so
there's a give and take there. in
previous drafts and granted you guys
drafted receivers the past two first
rounds but um you guys got a chance to
talk to Bryce right after the pick. Did
you guys get a chance to call him and
get his reaction to Monrell?
>> We have not.
>> No, I haven't. But he actually text me
and sounded pretty excited about it. So
that was that was a good text.
>> Say
>> I think just like let's go with
exclamation points. So I think Bryce is
pretty happy. the guy that that blocked
for Trevor at Georgia, were you able to
pick his brain at all on kind of what he
offers?
>> No, we weren't.
>> How did uh last year the way the O line
kind of shook out that there were so
many different combinations of guys who
needed to be flexible kind of play into
this pick knowing that you were getting
a versatile guy who could be doing
something like what you saw last year
out of your O line group?
>> Yeah, I think you know Dan said it um
for us like we're always trying to add
value to the fronts, both sides. uh
whether it was in free agency or the
draft. Um you know with the two edge
rushers last year with Nick and
Princeley um free agency with Bobby and
Turk getting those guys in here. Um you
know there's you can always help your
team by solidifying your front and by
adding talent that way. And uh so we're
we're so glad it worked out this way
because it is along that vein, you know,
to to continue to get guys into both of
those rooms because as we've seen, we
play with a lot of combinations of
offensive linemen over the last two
years and not just us, but around the
league, you know, that um that happens
to teams. So, it's it's uh it's
comforting to know that you have a room
full of really talented uh athletes.
>> You guys entered free agency with two
offensive tackles under under contract.
One just came off a major surgery. Now
you guys have kind of I think you're at
five now. What is your level of
confidence in that room in general and
you know falling tonight?
>> Yeah, I think uh we feel really good
about it. You know, I think um you know
we might not be done there. Um I think
that's uh again like we want to we want
to make both offensive line defensive
line as strong as possible. So, um, we
feel good about it right now, but, um,
we'll continue to add if we if we see,
you know, guys we like the rest of the
draft.
>> Or Dave, you guys have been reluctant to
give us much of a timeline on say he's
doing well. We saw some video of him
walking in the building. Can you give us
a better idea when you think you might
get him back?
>> He's again, he's doing great. He's
making a lot of progress. In terms of
timeline, I I don't have that for you.
>> Does that uncertain timeline, I'm sorry,
Scott, did that factor into this pick?
>> No, it was best player available.
Somebody that we felt like was a great
player that that we thought could help
our team and that was it.
>> Dave, um you keep talking about how
athletic this guy is. Is he a possible
tackle eligible pass receiver? I gotta
see I gotta see what kind of hands we're
dealing with here. But um we definitely
use a big tight end. So, you know, if he
doesn't win a job, he's going to play
some way, shape, or form. Uh because
he's just such a talent.
>> Do you feel like either of you guys you
feel like he's better on one side or the
other right?
>> Well, there's certainly more evidence on
the left, but with this athleticism,
he'll be able to do both in time.
>> With it used to be that like the left
tackle was your athletic guy and the
right tackle would be more your bruiser.
Do you feel like the league's caught up
to where both of those positions are
just as important and just as athletic?
>> Yeah, I mean I think so. I think, you
know, you need to have an athlete on
both sides. I mean, the rushers nowadays
are getting more and more athletic and
faster, bigger, stronger. So, um I think
if you can have athletes on both sides,
I mean that's ideal.
>> Thank you very much. All right. Thank
you.
I got